Finding Aid for the Kenneth Macgowan Papers LSC.0887
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Activities as an Educator
  - Correspondence and Ephemera re Harvard University
    - The Harvard Monthly; various issues., 1908-April 1909.; 5 items. (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - The Harvard Monthly; various issues., May-June 1909.; 2 items. (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - The Harvard Monthly; various issues., April-June 1911.; 3 items. (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Harvard summer news. Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1962.; 15 issues. vol.9 no.1-15. (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - UCLA, Material Relating Particularly to the Theater Arts Department
    - Correspondence, inter-departmental memos, reports, etc., re the Theater Arts Department, UCLA. v.p., 1946-1961.; 31 items. (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence between K. Macgowan and Ralph Freud, re the Theater Arts Deartment. Los Angeles, 1947-1957.; 38 items. (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Material re candidates for chairman of the Theater Arts Department. v.p., 1955-1957.; 26 items. (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Material re Arthur Ripley and the Theater Arts Department. v.p., 1955-1961.; 25 items. (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Material re curriculum for the Theater Arts Deartment. Los Angeles, v.d.; ca. 50 items. (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence re donations to the Theater Arts Department. v.p., 1949-1961.; 24 items. (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Carbon copies and drafts of letters from K. Macgowan to various persons re donations to the Theater Arts Department., ca. 85 items. (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with and about Sol Lesser, re donations to the Theater Arts Deartment. Los Angeles, 1956-1957.; 17 items. (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with William Perlberg re donations to the Theater Arts Deartment. Los Angeles, 1956-1960.; 18 items. (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with Charles E. Trezona Jr. re donations to the Theater Arts Deartment. Los Angeles and Beverly Hills, 1951-1955.; 15 items. (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Notes, lists, drafts of letters, and fragments re donors and donations to the Theater Arts Deartment. Los Angeles, 1949-1961.; ca. 50 items. (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence and ephemera re the American Educational Theatre Association. v.p., 1956-1961.; 20 items. (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Material re the American Education Theatre Association, Manuscript Play Project. v.p., 1951-1955.; 8 items. (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - Macgowan, Kenneth, 1888-1963. Educational Theatre of Tomorrow. Los Angeles, 1957.; 23 leaves. Typescript. (Box 58, Folder 14)
    - Macgowan, Kenneth, 1888-1963. Educational Theatre of Tomorrow. Los Angeles, 1957.; 5 items. (Box 58, Folder 15)
      Included are 1 carbon and 4 reprints.
    - Material re various societies for theater research. v.p., v.d.; 8 items. (Box 58, Folder 16)
    - Announcements and memorandums re the Motion Picture Division of the Theater Arts Deartment. Los Angeles, v.d.; 5 items. (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence re the Motion Picture Division. Los Angeles, v.d.; 24 items (Including ephemera). (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence with Norman Bel Geddes re Motion Picture Division. v.p., 1952.; 5 items. (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Richard J. Goggin and material re him, v.p., 1951-1953.; 25 items. (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Material re the curriculum of the Motion Picture, Radio and T.V. divisions of the Theater Arts Department., 12 items. (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Budget reports and financial statements of the Motion Picture Division. Los Angeles, v.d.; 11 items. (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Goals of the Motion Picture Division., 7 items. (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Material re students in the Motion Picture Division., 2 items. (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Material re Theater Arts film awards given to films of students of the Motion Picture Division. v.p., 1951-1960.; 30 items. (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Material re Television Kinescope Library. Los Angeles, 1956.; 3 items. (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Material re Radio Division, particularly the dismissal of W. David Sievers. Los Angeles, 1950.; 16 items. (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Articles by K. Macgowan re teaching of theater, film and T.V. in the University. Los Angeles, v.d.; 13 items. Typescript. (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Articles by K. Macgowan re teaching of theater, film and T.V. in the University. Los Angeles, v.d.; 8 items. (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, manuscript and notes re article by K. Macgowan on the new play and playwright in the universities. v.p., 1955.; 10 items. (Box 59, Folder 14)
  - UCLA, Material re Kenneth Macgowan's Role as Teacher, His Classes, Retirement from UCLA, etc.
    - Material re English 106D playwrighting class, taught by K. Macgowan. Los Angeles, n.d.; 30 items. (Box 60, Folder 1)
      Includes student biographies and mimeograph forms.
    - Student biographies from English 106D, playwrighting class taught by K. Macgowan. Los Angeles, n.d.; 26 items. (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Student biographies from playwrighting classes taught by K. Macgowan. Los Angeles, ca. 1951-1953.; ca. 100 items. (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Student evaluations of classes taught by K. Macgowan, plus miscellaneous material re theater arts classes. Los Angeles, 1950-1951.; 8 items. (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Material re the One Act Play Program at UCLA. Los Angeles, v.d.; 7 items. (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous material re tests., 6 items. (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Outlines for class lectures by K. Macgowan., 2 items. (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Material re the Theater Arts Departmental Library. Los Angeles, 1947-1950.; 5 items. (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous material re students., 4 items. (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Material re the appointment of K. Macgowan as Professor of Theater Arts at UCLA. Los Angeles, June 1946.; 8 items. (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, ephemera, and manuscripts re K. Macgowan's retirement from UCLA. v.p., 1952-1959.; 64 items. (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Theater program for the UCLA T.A. Production of Caesar and Cleopatra dedicated to K. Macgowan. Los Angeles, May 1956.; 6 copies of the program. (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Lecture notes on cards for K. Macgowan's playwrighting class., ca. 100 cards. (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - Notes and various cards re K. Macgowan's class lectures., ca. 100 items. (Box 60, Folder 14)
  - UCLA. Notes On Cards Used in Class Lecture by Kenneth Macgowan
    - Notes on cards used in class lectures by K. Macgowan., ca. 500 cards. (Box 61, Folder 1 - 6)
  - Clippings Used as Research Material by Kenneth Macgowan in Compiling Lecture Notes
    - Clippings used by K. Macgowan in compiling lecture notes. v.p., and some, 1950-1958 n.d.; ca. 490 items. (Folder 1, Folder 2, Folder 3, Folder 4, Folder 5, Folder 6, Folder 7, Folder 8, Folder 9, Folder 10, Folder 11, Folder 12, Folder 13, Folder 14)
  - UCLA. Lecture Notes on Cards Material re UCLA Extension Theatre Group
    - Lecture notes. v.p., v.d.; ca. 100 items. (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Lecture notes. v.p., v.d.; ca. 100 items. (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Lecture notes. v.p., v.d.; ca. 100 items. (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Material re the University Extension Theatre Group. Los Angeles, v.d.; 6 items. (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and newspaper clippings re University Extension Theatre Group. v.p., v.d.; 34 items. (Includes many duplicates of clippings). (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Various records, lists, programs, minutes, etc. re University Extension Theatre Group. Los Angeles, 1958-1963.; ca. 50 items. (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - UCLA. Material re the Theatre Arts Building Project
    - Correspondence re the Theater Arts Project. Los Angeles, 1952-1960.; 6 items. (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Article entitled Exterior problems, with no author indicated. n.p., 19 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Plans, reports, lists and other material re the Theater Arts Building Project. Los Angeles, 1956-1963.; 11 items. (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous building ideas. v.p., v.d.; 15 items. (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Photographs and plans of various building designs., 37 items. (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Motion picture building plans. Los Angeles, 1949.; 1 item. (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - UCLA. Material re Various Aspects of the University
    - Material re the UCLA Academic Senate., 3 items. (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Catalog of the Arensberg Collection of Art., 1 item. (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, reports, contracts, and other material re the Arensberg Collection of Art. v.p., v.d.; 43 items. (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Material re the Francis Bacon Foundation and the Arensberg Collection of Art, given to UCLA., 7 items. (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Material re the proposed UCLA Art Museum as related to the Arensberg Collection of Art., 12 items. (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and announcements re various aspects of the University K. Macgowan was associated with., 19 items. (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence of K. Macgowan and the UCLA Library., 18 items. (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Speech on the Sixth Founder's Day Celebration of the William Andrew Clark Library. Los Angeles, 1932.; 7 leaves. Typescript (carbon). (Box 65, Folder 8)
      Includes 2 printed copies.
    - Correspondence, memos and other material re Honorary Degrees given at UCLA. Los Angeles, 1959-1963.; ca. 55 items. (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Lists of honorary degrees awarded, clipped notes and résumés. n.p., 42 items. (All are copies). (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence and ephemera re the Integrated Arts Program at UCLA. v.p., 1946-1962.; ca. 60 items. (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous ephemera., ca. 40 items. (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - Ephemera re education. v.p., v.d.; 8 items. (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - Material re the Quarterly of Film, Radio and Television, published by the UC Press. v.p., v.d.; ca. 85 items. (Includes 1 issue). (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Working manual and by-laws for the Quarterly.... n.p., 4 items. Typescript (mostly carbon). (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous notes and fragments re the Quarterly...., ca. 50 items. Typescript (carbon) and holograph. (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Printed articles by Kenneth Macgowan that appeared in the Quarterly.... Berkeley, 1946-1955.; 19 items. (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Printed articles by K. Macgowan that appeared in the Quarterly.... Berkeley, 1956-1957.; 10 items. (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Material re K. Macgowan and UCLA Radio Broadcasts, plus printed copies of various broadcasts. Los Angeles, v.d.; 13 items. (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Printed articles about theater, motion pictures and UCLA by K. Macgowan. v.p., v.d.; 3 items. (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Ephemera re UCLA as a whole. v.p., v.d.; 26 items. (Many duplicates). (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Ephemera re UCLA, particularly the Theater Arts and Motion Picture Departments. v.p., v.d.; 46 items. (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Ephemera re teaching theater and motion picture arts in the University. v.p., v.d.; 11 items. (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - UCLA. Material re the University of California Loyalty Oath Controversy
    - Correspondence and notes re the University of California Loyalty Oath Controversy. v.p., 1949-1951.; 29 items. (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous leaves of manuscript, drafts of letters and statements re the Loyalty Oath Controversy., ca. 20 items. (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence re U.S. State Department's refusal of passport for K. Macgowan. v.p., 1953.; ca. 25 items. (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Articles re academic freedom and the Loyalty Oath Controversy. v.p., 1949-1956.; 29 items. (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous mimeograph and photocopy material re UC Loyalty Oath Controversy. California, v.d.; 14 items. (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Pamphlets and a reprint of an article re the UC Loyalty Oath Controversy. California, v.d.; 4 items. (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence. A - J
    - Correspondence - A -., 34 items. (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - B -., 44 items. (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence - C -., 78 items. (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - D -., 24 items. (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - E -., 40 items. (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence - F -., 21 items. (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - Faragoh, Francis Edward., 40 items. (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence - Filer, Tom., 11 items. (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence - G -., 32 items. (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence - H -., 50 items. (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence - Heyward, Leland and Myron Selznick., 32 items. (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence - I -., 2 items. (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence - J -., 2 items. (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence - Jones, Robert Edmond., 57 items. (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence - Jones, Robert Edmond., 35 items. Undated letters and ephemera. (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence - Jones, Robert Edmond., 25 items. (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Jones, Robert Edmond. Macgowan, Kenneth. (Box 68, Folder 17)
      - Jones as director...designer. Los Angeles, n.d.; 2 copies, 1 partial. Typescript (carbon). (Box 68, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence. K - R
    - Correspondence - K -., 20 items. (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - L -., 15 items. (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence - La Jolla-San Diego Theatre and Arts Foundation., 33 items. (Includes ephemera). (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - Lindsey, Ben., 14 items. (Includes ephemera). (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - Lux, Louise and her life story., 14 items. (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence - M -., 39 items. (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - Macgowan, Kenneth. Miscellaneous drafts and carbons of letters to various persons., 35 items. (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence - Macgowan, Kenneth. Letters and ephemera re his auto and gas rations in the, 1940's.; 36 items. (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence - Macgowan, Kenneth. Material re his insurance., 5 items. (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence - Macgowna, Kenneth. Miscellaneous personal papers, records, receipts, etc., 21 items. (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence - Mamoulian, Rouben., 8 items. (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence - The Modern Forum, Incorporated., 18 items. (Includes ephemera). (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence - Motion Picture Industry Council, Incorporated., 8 items. (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence - M, Hiram K., 26 items. (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence - N -., 27 items. (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence - O - P - Q., 57 items. (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence - Pan American Union. Washington, D.C., 9 items. (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence - Pichel, Irving., 50 items. (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence - R -., 28 items. (Box 69, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence. S - Z
    - Correspondence - S -., 20 items. (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence - Schnitzler, Henry., 10 items. (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence - The International Arthur Schnitzler Research Association., 4 items. (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - Shaw, George Bernard., 100 items. (Includes many copies). (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence - Shaw, George Bernard. Much corres. re The Devil's Disciple..., 54 items. (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence - The Devil's Disciple, by George Bernard Shaw., 26 items. (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence - The Devil's Disciple, by George Bernard Shaw., 35 items. (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence - T - U., 21 items. (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence - V-W-X-Y-Z., 27 items. (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence - Whitney, John Hay and the John Hay Whitney Foundation., 7 items. (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence - Unidentified., 46 items. (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence - Miscellaneous fragments and drafts., ca. 50 items. (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence - Miscellaneous cards, notes and lists., ca. 30 items. (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence re Kenneth Macgowan. v.p., v.d.; 4 items. Typescript. (Includes 1 enclosure). (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence between various persons included in the K. Macgowan Collection. v.p., v.d.; 4 items. Holograph and typescript (some carbon). (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - Excerpts from letters and wires between K. Macgowan and various persons. n.p., November 1933-March 1, 1934.; 1 item. Various carbon copies bound in a brown paper folder. (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - Excerpts from lettera and wires between K. Macgowan and various persons. n.p., March 2, 1934-July 1934.; 1 item. Various carbon copies bound in a paper folder. (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - Excerpts from letters and wires between K. Macgowan and various persons. n.p., August 1934.; 1 item. Various copies in a paper folder. (Box 70, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence. Simonson, Lee, 1888-
    - Correspondence between Lee Simonson and K. Macgowan. v.p., 1927-1939.; 33 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence between Lee Simonson and K. Macgowan. v.p., 1940-1943.; 37 items. (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence between Lee Simonson and K. Macgowan. v.p., 1944-1945.; 31 items. (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence between Lee Simonson and K. Macgowan. v.p., 1946.; 17 items. (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence between Lee Simonson and K. Macgowan. v.p., 1947.; 27 items. (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence between Lee Simonson and K. Macgowan. v.p., January-April 1948.; 23 items. (Including enclosures). Holograph and typescript. (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence between Lee Simonson and K. Macgowan. v.p., 1948-1950.; 25 items. (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence between Lee Simonson and K. Macgowan. v.p., 1951-1959.; 19 items including enclosures. (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Letters from Lee Simonson to K. Macgowan. v.p., n.d.; 7 items. Holograph. (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence between various persons about Lee Simonson. v.p., 1944-1959.; 36 items. Holograph and typescript (much carbon). (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence between members of the Simonson family and K. Macgowan. v.p., 1944-1959.; 18 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Article and quote of Lee Simonson. n.p., 2 items. Printed. (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Articles about Lee Simonson by K. Macgowan. v.p., v.d.; 3 items. (Box 71, Folder 13)
      Includes 1 typescript and 2 clippings.
    - Material re decline of New York and American theaters received by K. Macgowan from lee Simonson., 25 items. (Many duplicates of statistics). (Box 71, Folder 14)
      Includes clippings.
  - Correspondence and Material re the Film The Maya Through The Ages
    - Correspondence between Giles Healey and K. Macgowan re the film The Maya through the ages. v.p., 1944.; 41 items. Holograph and typescript. (Folder 1)
    - Correspondence between Giles Healey and K. Macgowan.... v.p., 1945-1960.; ca. 115 items. (Box 72, Folder 2)
      Includes enclosures
    - Correspondence between Giles Healey and K. Macgowan.... v.p., 1944-1957.; 30 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence between J. Eric S. Thompson and K. Macgowan re the film The Maya through the ages. v.p., 1941-1949.; ca. 75 items. (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence between the United Fruit Company and K. Macgowan re the film The Maya through the ages. v.p., 1947-1949.; 16 items. Typescript. (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence between Edmund S. Whitman and K. Macgowan re the film The Maya through the ages. v.p., January-May 1948.; 63 items. (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence between Edmund S. Whitman and K. Macgowan.... v.p., June-December 1948.; ca. 110 items. (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence between Edmund S. Whitman and K. Macgowan... v.p., January-August 1949.; ca. 95 items. (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence between Edmund S. Whitman and K. Macgowan.... v.p., September 1949-1953.; 79 items. (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence between Charles M. Wilson and K. Magowan.... v.p., 1944-1948.; 92 items. (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence between K. Macgowan and various persons re the film The Maya through the ages. v.p., 1944-1949.; 84 items. (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence of K. Macgowan and the Carnegie Institute re The Maya through the ages. v.p., 1942-1948.; 17 items. (Includes 1 ephemera, Annual Report, 1963). (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence of K. Macgowan and A.V. Kidder of the Carnegie Institute. v.p., 1942-1949.; 70 items. (Box 73, Folder 3)
      Includes 1 ephemera.
    - Narration for the film The Maya through the ages. n.p., n.d.; 5 items. Typescript (much carbon, 3 duplicates). (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous leaves of mss. for the narration ot the film The Maya through the ages. n.p., n.d.; ca. 150 leaves. Typescript (carbon) with corrections. (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Plan for distribution for The Maya through the ages. (California, n.d.; 1 item. Typescript (carbon). In a green paper cover. (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Maya present, Maya past. Manuscript re the film The Maya through the ages. n.p., n.d.; 5 items. Typescript (carbon). Chapters I and V. (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous manuscript material and notes re the film The Maya through the ages. n.p., 8 items. Typescript (much carbon). (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Financial and other records re the film The Maya through the ages. v.p., v.d.; 12 items. (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Ephemera re the film The Maya through the ages. v.p., v.d.; 14 items. (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Various film shooting records and scene notes for The Maya through the ages. n.p., 5 items. (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous material used in making the film The Maya through the ages.., 12 items. (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous material used in making the film The Maya through the ages.., 26 items. (Box 74, Folder 3)
- Additional Material (), June 1966
  - Books and Pamphlets re Anthropology and Archaeology
    - Books re anthropology and archaeology., 8 items. (Box 75)
    - Pamphlets re anthropology and archaeology., 5 items. (Box 75)
  - Behind The Screen: The History and Technique of the Motion Picture
    - Completed Typescript as Returned From the Publisher
      - Macgowan, Kenneth, 1888-1963. Behind the screen... completed typescript as returned from the publisher., Chapters 1 - 32. (Box 76, Folder 1 - 6)
    - Research Material, Mostly Notes, re the Work [Behind the screen......]
      - Research material, mostly notes, for Behind the screen......, ca. 60 items. Typescript, holograph and printed. (Box 77, Folder 1 - 10)
    - Early Drafts of Chapters. Research Material, Notes
      - Early drafts of chapters for Behind the screen.... Chapters 4-6, Typescript. (Box 78, Folder 1)
      - Early drafts of chapters for Behind the screen.... Chapters 7-9. Typescript. (Box 78, Folder 2)
      - Early drafts of chapters for Behind the screen.... Chapter 18. Typescript and photocopy. (Box 78, Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous leaves of manuscript for Behind the screen......, ca. 25 leaves. Typescript (some carbon). (Box 78, Folder 4)
      - Research material about the movie The Jazz Singer, used for Behind the screen......, ca. 15 leaves. (Box 78, Folder 5)
      - Research material, mostly notes, for chapters 1 and 2, of Behind the screen......, ca. 25 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 78, Folder 6)
      - Research material, mostly notes for Behind the screen.... Typescript on small slips of paper. (Box 78, Folder 7)
      - Research material, mostly notes, for Behind the screen.... Typescript on small slips of paper, with some holograph notes. (Box 78, Folder 8)
      - Clippings from newspapers and periodicals used in research for Behind the screen.... v.p., v.d.; ca. 50 items. (Box 78, Folder 9)
      - Clippings from newspapers and periodicals used in research for Behind the screen.... v.p., v.d.; ca. 65 items. (Box 78, Folder 10)